<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-29T12:05:38-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Health, Healing, and Hope (H3)</title><subtitle>Join me as I catalog my journey of the peaks and valleys of health, healing, and hope (H3 with Laura). I want to share some of my favorite paleo, gluten free, refined sugar-free, and egg free recipes. I hope to share my thoughts on health related topics and provide meaningful tips.</subtitle><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><entry><title type="html">Blueberry Scone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/29/Blueberry-Scone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blueberry Scone" /><published>2020-09-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/29/Blueberry-Scone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/29/Blueberry-Scone/">&lt;p&gt;Anyone else have blueberries in your fridge or freezer? Growing up in Alaska we would always pick blueberries in August and September. So before I go all pumpkin and apple, I thought I would share my mini blueberry scone recipe. I personally like mini size but if you like the bakery style size just double the recipe! These are paleo, egg free and easily made vegan by using vegan butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00DOKFLYI/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00DOKFLYI&amp;amp;linkId=06c100c0b80203f02a228dabea5ca73f&quot;&gt;flax egg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons unsalted grass-fed or vegan butter softened and cubed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup plus 2 tablespoons &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00CLLV2D0/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00CLLV2D0&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;linkId=95d673b6047b5d309c17d3e4b4fdb312&quot;&gt;almond flour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00VQO4YJC/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00VQO4YJC&amp;amp;linkId=9fb90abefdb414d2d4d5b93f92d98764&quot;&gt;tapioca flour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoons &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B074V3V186/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B074V3V186&amp;amp;linkId=c795a8d456d528de71906d10bbc46d47&quot;&gt;maple syrup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup frozen or fresh blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons unsweetened nut milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make flax egg by combining 1 tablespoons ground flaxseed and 2.5 tablespoons boiling water and let sit for 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together the almond flour, tapioca flour, baking powder, and fine sea salt in a medium sized bowl. Using either a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01CX1RIMQ/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01CX1RIMQ&amp;amp;linkId=9f41c94c1e4f8a33803a39c347dc6f22&quot;&gt;pastry cutter&lt;/a&gt;, two forks, or your hands, mix in the cubed butter until the mixture comes together in pea sized crumbs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl, mix together the flax egg, maple syrup, and vanilla. Pour over the flour mixture and mix until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in the frozen blueberries (do not thaw before) or fresh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover dough and freeze for thirty minutes. Freezing the dough makes it much easier to handle.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F and line a cookie sheet with parchment paper and spread a little tapioca flour on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the dough out of the freezer and place on floured parchment paper. Form an 8 inch disk and cut with a knife cut into 8 wedges. Freeze the cut dough for 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take out of the freezer and pull the scones at least 2 to 3 inches apart.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush scones with nut milk and bake for 18-25 (mine took 22)  minutes or until golden on top.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with &lt;a href=&quot;https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/25/thurs-birthday-cake/&quot;&gt;paleo powdered sugar&lt;/a&gt; if desired and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** They are best served warm right out of the oven. Store in the fridge for 5 days or at room temperature for a couple.
** If you want to make big bakery style scones you can double this recipe but you may need to bake it for longer&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><summary type="html">Anyone else have blueberries in your fridge or freezer? Growing up in Alaska we would always pick blueberries in August and September. So before I go all pumpkin and apple, I thought I would share my mini blueberry scone recipe. I personally like mini size but if you like the bakery style size just double the recipe! These are paleo, egg free and easily made vegan by using vegan butter.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1601398097/Blog/Mini_Blueberry_Scones_xdi8tl.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1601398097/Blog/Mini_Blueberry_Scones_xdi8tl.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Creamy Vegetable Soup</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/27/Creamy-Vegetable-Soup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creamy Vegetable Soup" /><published>2020-09-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/27/Creamy-Vegetable-Soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/27/Creamy-Vegetable-Soup/">&lt;p&gt;It is finally soup season! This soup is easy to make, full of vegetables and makes for a great lunch or dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ready in 45 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serves 8 people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paleo, Vegan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tablespoons &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00K4QF4HO/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00K4QF4HO&amp;amp;linkId=9b0453868737cf02f82eadac7f20924e&quot;&gt;avocado oil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 oz bag of frozen riced cauliflower (about 1 ¼ cup)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9 oz bag of fresh broccoli chopped finely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup diced butternut squash*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 small yellow onion chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup chopped carrots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01MYFLIA9/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01MYFLIA9&amp;amp;linkId=94aed141cd3aeb62c204df399b1d9e39&quot;&gt;arrowroot powder&lt;/a&gt; + 3 tablespoons water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ cups vegetable broth (or chicken if not vegan)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup unsweetened almond or cashew milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ vegan queso or nutritional yeast*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ lemon juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp fine sea salt (or to taste)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fresh ground pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a Dutch Oven or soup pot, over medium heat, add avocado oil, rice cauliflower, broccoli, butternut squash, onion and sauté for 5-7 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in garlic, salt, and pepper and sauté for a few more minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make arrowroot slurry by combining arrowroot powder and whisking until combined until no clumps remain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add vegetable broth, almond milk, vegan queso, and arrowroot slurry and bring to a boil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn heat to low and simmer for 15-30 minutes or until vegetables are tender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with crackers and vegan or regular cheese if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips
** I personally do not love the flavor of nutritional yeast so I added in a vegan queso. If you are not dairy free you could do cheese instead&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** If you do not have butternut squash feel free to use potato or sweet potato
** You can sub fresh veggies for frozen or vise versa&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="vegan" /><summary type="html">It is finally soup season! This soup is easy to make, full of vegetables and makes for a great lunch or dinner.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1601224792/Blog/Creamy_Vegetable_Soup_xip6it.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1601224792/Blog/Creamy_Vegetable_Soup_xip6it.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Relationship with Food (Part 3)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/23/My-Relationship-with-Food-Pt-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Relationship with Food (Part 3)" /><published>2020-09-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/23/My-Relationship-with-Food-Pt-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/23/My-Relationship-with-Food-Pt-3/">&lt;p&gt;Where I am now compared to 2 years ago is completely different. I healed most of my health and gut issues which means I am able to enjoy previous off limits foods (as in I could not tolerate them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I share my tips on where I am at now, I just want to say no journey looks the same. We may have similar stories or health issues but what my body can or cannot tolerate may be totally different than yours. I suggest taking the time to understand what food works best for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, there is hope. I came such a long way. There was a season of not being able to go out to eat anywhere, or staying home so I could be near a bathroom at all times. I truly believe, if we take the time to allow our bodies to heal, nourish it with nutrient dense food, sleep, and conduct adequate movement, healing is on the other side. Hold onto hope and keep fighting because my story is a testament that healing is possible and it will not last forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do an elimination diet- If you have never done one, it is a stellar way to understand what food is best for you. I did one even after I healed most of my gut issues and I discovered bad stomach pain after eating eggs. Once I eliminated those, I realized some of my prolonged gut issues were because of eggs. An elimination diet is really to help us discover if our body is reacting to certain foods. It is not meant to be long term.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out what are your “hard no’s” and your “sometimes”. Basically, I do not need to be paleo 100% of the time. My body can tolerate white rice and I enjoy it so is a “sometimes”. Corn on the other hand still causes bad bloating and other issues so that is a “hard no”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember it is a lifestyle not a diet-  As my body healed from a significant amount of my health issues, I did not have to be as strict with food as I used to be. I still believe in fueling my body with nutrient dense food which tends to align more with a paleo diet. However, I still enjoy non paleo foods. Make sure you are doing something sustainable and can be lasting. If your favorite food is corn chips and your body tolerates them, I would not restrict yourself from them. Focus on nutrient dense foods but you can still enjoy deviations from time to time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be honest with your weakness and plan according- I love salt, (I am actually more of a salt lover than a sweet lover). Going to a Mexican restaurant where they serve chips and salsa  is a good way to cause pain later. If going out for Mexican food, I pack my own chips. I still enjoy the salsa and guac with everyone but do not cause myself serious stomach pain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop punishing yourself- There have been times when I ate a big dinner with dessert and thought to myself- “I’ll just eat less tomorrow”. Yet, no matter how much I eat today, my body still needs to eat tomorrow. Food is fuel and medicine for our bodies. I am relearning how I think of food, and how I view myself in light of the food I eat. I want to feel good so I fuel my body accordingly but I also want to enjoy an apple crisp from time to time. I do both but without the shame and guilt I used to put on myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><summary type="html">Where I am now compared to 2 years ago is completely different. I healed most of my health and gut issues which means I am able to enjoy previous off limits foods (as in I could not tolerate them).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600975583/Blog/Relationship_with_food_part3_ir0qpc.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600975583/Blog/Relationship_with_food_part3_ir0qpc.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pumpkin Bread</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/Pumpkin-Bread/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pumpkin Bread" /><published>2020-09-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/Pumpkin-Bread</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/22/Pumpkin-Bread/">&lt;p&gt;Fall is officially here! This recipe is a labor of love! It took four times to perfect it but it was worth the effort! This is gluten free, egg free, and easily made vegan by using vegan butter. I personally love pumpkin bread with a glaze but you can also do chocolate chips. Happy Fall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients
Bread:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 tablespoons unsalted grass-fed butter*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 can pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B082DBXXR6/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B082DBXXR6&amp;amp;linkId=63e5b4c0f205e3682c37a6010bbff3fd&quot;&gt;maple syrup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 flax eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ¾ cup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01JJ9H1Q8/ref=as_li_qf_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=h3withlaura-20&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01JJ9H1Q8&amp;amp;linkId=97fa717ff0f6360a1ee5dd249e825f88&quot;&gt;King Arthur gluten free flour&lt;/a&gt;*&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon pumpkin pie spice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: Chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maple Glaze:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup maple sugar powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoons unsweetened nut milk (or more if you want it thinner)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon vanilla extract (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F and line an 8 ½ by 4 ½ inch loaf pan with parchment paper and spray with coconut oil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut butter into slices and add to a saucepan over medium high heat. Cook until butter starts to foam and turns a light brown color. It should start to smell “nutty”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immediately transfer butter into a bowl and let it cool. It should be a light brown color. Let cool for at least 15 minutes. You can easily just melt the butter and not brown it but this gives the bread such a yummy flavor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 2 tablespoons ground flaxseed and 5 tablespoons boiling water and let sit for at least 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium sized bowl, mix together all the dry ingredients (except chocolate chips if using).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large mixing bowl, add the pumpkin puree, maple syrup, flax eggs, and vanilla extract.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk together until smooth and slowly whisk in the browned butter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the dry ingredients into the wet and mix until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in chocolate chips if using.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour batter into the loaf pan evenly and bake for 55-60 minutes (mine took 58 mins).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow bread to cool for 15 minutes and then remove and cool on a wire rack.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make maple glaze, combine all the ingredients in a bowl and whisk until smooth. Pour over cooled pumpkin bread and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips:
** If using vegan butter I suggest using a stick of butter and not the spreadable kind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt; I use King Arthur gluten free flour because it does not have corn in it, however it does use grains so it is not paleo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="desserts" /><summary type="html">Fall is officially here! This recipe is a labor of love! It took four times to perfect it but it was worth the effort! This is gluten free, egg free, and easily made vegan by using vegan butter. I personally love pumpkin bread with a glaze but you can also do chocolate chips. Happy Fall!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600801374/Blog/Pumpkin_Bread_nfogik.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600801374/Blog/Pumpkin_Bread_nfogik.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Relationship with Food (Part 2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Thurs-My-Relationship-with-Food-Part-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Relationship with Food (Part 2)" /><published>2020-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Thurs-My-Relationship-with-Food-Part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/17/Thurs-My-Relationship-with-Food-Part-2/">&lt;p&gt;When I noticed my stomach worse, I switched to paleo about a year ago and continue to follow it now. No matter what I ate, even if it was raw almonds, chicken, or roasted veggies, my stomach would hurt and become bloated. During the same time, I navigated a season of rest which meant most of my days were spent in bed. The season allowed my body to recover and heal. As a result, even with trying to do everything right but still having my stomach health plummet, battling through proved taxing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were times when I did not eat because hunger proved easier to deal with than stomach pain . There were times I ate a bowl of rice as it was all I could tolerate. The season was extremely exigent. I felt like food or rather the lack of food controlled me. I need to be near a bathroom. I could not eat at any restaurants and numerous nights I laid awake in pain. There are a handful of things I did in this season to help my gut heal. This is by no means advice on what to do. I am just sharing what worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat what your body can tolerate- I lived on smoothies and rice for months. As I started to figure out what was going on, I changed what I ate as it was more important to eat than be strictly paleo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start a food journal- For a couple months, I tracked everything I ate which allowed me to understand my body as it reacted to certain foods.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a practitioner who understands gut health- I discovered symptoms of something called IBS- Irritable Bowel Syndrome. Once I started treating with supplements, and a more strict food diet, I started to see improvements. Then as I discovered my root cause of IBS, I saw even more healing (will share more on this next week).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritize sleep- Sleep is so important and most of us do not get enough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduce Stress- Find ways to manage stress and relax. It is crucial in helping heal gut issues. I decided to not work and reduce my high intensity workouts. Reducing stress can look different for everyone so whether it is yoga, meditation, or working only part time find a way to reduce your stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Say what you need- For me this time was already punishing but it can be even more difficult doing it alone. Walking through it with my husband was a huge help. He knew I needed to be near a bathroom, most nights we would spend watching a movie and going out to eat just was not possible. People want to help but they can only do so if we allow them and tell them what we need. Be honest with the loved ones around you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><summary type="html">When I noticed my stomach worse, I switched to paleo about a year ago and continue to follow it now. No matter what I ate, even if it was raw almonds, chicken, or roasted veggies, my stomach would hurt and become bloated. During the same time, I navigated a season of rest which meant most of my days were spent in bed. The season allowed my body to recover and heal. As a result, even with trying to do everything right but still having my stomach health plummet, battling through proved taxing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600370804/Blog/Relationship_with_Food_Part_2_ng2ikz.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600370804/Blog/Relationship_with_Food_Part_2_ng2ikz.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Ingredient Pumpkin Cookies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/Pumpkin-Cookies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Ingredient Pumpkin Cookies" /><published>2020-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/Pumpkin-Cookies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/15/Pumpkin-Cookies/">&lt;p&gt;These are the easiest pumpkin cookies you will ever make. I used Simple Mills cake mix to keep it paleo but feel free to use whatever you have in your pantry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paleo, Vegan and Oil Free&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 box simple mills vanilla cake mix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup pure pumpkin puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾  teaspoon pumpkin pie spice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 375 degrees F and line a cookie sheet with parchment paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium sized bowl  mix cake mix, pumpkin puree and pumpkin pie spice until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in chocolate chips.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scoop dough onto the cookie sheet and bake for 12-15 minutes (mine took 14).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool on a wire rack and leave at room temperature for a day or store in the fridge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tips
** You can also turn these into cupcakes/muffins just bake for 20-25 minutes&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="desserts" /><category term="easy" /><summary type="html">These are the easiest pumpkin cookies you will ever make. I used Simple Mills cake mix to keep it paleo but feel free to use whatever you have in your pantry!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600179676/Blog/Pumpkin-Cookies_1_sbfgvd.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1600179676/Blog/Pumpkin-Cookies_1_sbfgvd.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Skillet Cookie with Carmel Sauce</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/Cookie-Skillet-with-Carmel-Sauce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skillet Cookie with Carmel Sauce" /><published>2020-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/Cookie-Skillet-with-Carmel-Sauce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/Cookie-Skillet-with-Carmel-Sauce/">&lt;p&gt;When I lived in Anchorage, a local restaurant did a cookie skillet with caramel sauce and ice cream on top. They served it warm and it was to die for. I still think about it so I decided to create a paleo and egg free version. The caramel sauce is optional but highly encouraged. Serve in slices or eat it straight from the pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients
Cookie Skillet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 flax eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 tablespoons softened unsalted grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tablespoons maple sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup unsalted cashew butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ¾ cup almond flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10 almond butter cups or 1 cashew chocolate Hu Kitchen bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caramel Pecan Sauce: (optional)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup pure maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons pecan butter (I used salted)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dash of salt (if your nut butter is not salted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 1 Tbsp ground flaxseed and 2.5 Tbsp of boiling water and let sit for at least 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small bowl, whisk together the dry ingredients (except chopped almond butter cups).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a mixing bowl, cream the butter and maple sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then add the vanilla extract, flax egg, and cashew butter to the mixing bowl. Mix until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the dry ingredients to the wet and mix until a sticky dough is formed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in the almond butter cups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spray cake pan with coconut oil and evenly spread out the dough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkle the remainder of almond butter cups pressing them down slightly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with plastic wrap and place in the fridge for 2 hours or overnight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 350(F) degrees.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 15-22 minutes (mine took about 18, it should look a little underdone in the middle).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If making caramel pecan sauce, while the cookie skillet is baking, in a small saucepan over medium heat, add all the ingredients for the caramel pecan sauce. Whisk until all the ingredients are mixed and become smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil and whisk continuously for about a minute or until the sauce starts to thicken up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool for at least 15 minutes before serving and drizzle with caramel pecan sauce..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best enjoyed with vanilla ice cream on top. Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** The cashew butter I used had salt in it, if yours doesn’t you may want to up the amount of salt you add to ¼ teaspoon. If you don’t have almond butter cups just add chocolate chips!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="desserts" /><summary type="html">When I lived in Anchorage, a local restaurant did a cookie skillet with caramel sauce and ice cream on top. They served it warm and it was to die for. I still think about it so I decided to create a paleo and egg free version. The caramel sauce is optional but highly encouraged. Serve in slices or eat it straight from the pan.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1599849338/Blog/cookie_skillet_jqcby5.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1599849338/Blog/cookie_skillet_jqcby5.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Relationship with Food</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/10/Thurs-My-Relationship-with-Food/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Relationship with Food" /><published>2020-09-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/10/Thurs-My-Relationship-with-Food</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/10/Thurs-My-Relationship-with-Food/">&lt;p&gt;I figured breaking this into three different posts would be easiest. My relationship with food changed over the years. I want to share what I did when the stomach/health issues flared, what I did when I was at my worst, and where I am at now after seeing significant healing and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am doing now and can tolerate is different than what I did three years ago. The three parts will be going paleo, eating paleo as my stomach issues worsened, and actions now the root cause healed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went from eating normal to paleo overnight. Unless your primary care practitioner tells you to change overnight, I would not recommend it. It can be overwhelming and frustrating. If you are trying to eat similar to a paleo lifestyle, I recommend making changes one at a time and going slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transitioning from a current way of eating to paleo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research- take the time to research paleo. It is different from what most of us are used to eating. Set yourself up for success by understanding what types of paleo foods, brands to look for in stores, and recipes you can start introducing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go slowly- try eliminating one item at a time (start with any of the following and then move to the another one: gluten, sugar, diary, grains, soy, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replace pantry items as you run out- overhauling your entire panty can be expensive and wasteful. I recommend starting slowly. Once you run out of normal flour buy almond. Stock up on nuts and seeds for snacks, healthier oils for cooking, and dried fruit for when sugar cravings hit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go off all sugar (even natural like honey and maple syrup) for at least 10 days- our bodies are easily addicted to refined sugar. When we go off of it, even switching to natural, we are not really killing the addiction. Try only eating fruit for 10-30 days before adding in honey, maple syrup, or coconut sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replace refrigerated items- you will be surprised with how many condiments and dressing have sugar and high inflammatory oils.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meal prep- plan easy lunch and snack items ready to go in your refrigerator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Host at your house- I could do an entire post on this one but it can be problematic  to go out to restaurants and over to friends houses when trying to strictly eat paleo. I generally try to host if I can, or pick the restaurant and look at the menu ahead of time. I also pack items to supplement meals out or at friends- like salad dressing, paleo crackers etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have your spouse or friend do it with you- it can feel like a grind for the first month or so. Having an accountability partner and not having to cook two meals makes all the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><summary type="html">I figured breaking this into three different posts would be easiest. My relationship with food changed over the years. I want to share what I did when the stomach/health issues flared, what I did when I was at my worst, and where I am at now after seeing significant healing and improvement.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1599741867/Blog/salad-bowl_ssjzjt.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1599741867/Blog/salad-bowl_ssjzjt.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Relationship with Food</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/08/Tues-Food-Relationship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Relationship with Food" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/08/Tues-Food-Relationship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/08/Tues-Food-Relationship/">&lt;p&gt;When was the last time you asked yourself about your relationship with food?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, mine has been substandard at times and superb at other times. Growing up overweight resulted in quite a bit of thought about what I ate. I dwelled on the 2 Eggo waffles I ate instead of 1, the cake at the birthday party, the second helping I wanted of my Mom’s dinner but felt I did not deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to when I was trying to lose the weight and I would not allow myself things like cereal, bread, cookies, chips etc. I counted every calorie and shamed myself for even wanting a sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I lost the weight but I never knew if what I ate was going to hurt my stomach or make me feel bad. Instead of not eating things out of shame I did not eat things out of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where am I now? To be honest I am still figuring it out. There are times I do not want to eat dessert because the voice of shame comes back because I am fearful about causing gut issues. Finding balance when it comes to food is not easy and is a daily practice. I fuel my body with nutrients and I am mindful about the number of treats consumed. I also recognize the joy I experience baking and from hosting and gathering around a table. There are days when my body needs a salad but there are days I need some avocado toast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am learning to honor my body and my hunger instead of shaming it. It is not a one and done but a daily practice. I am choosing to fuel and nourish my body with an array of vegetables, fruits, healthy fats and protein but I am also choosing to have the homemade peach cobbler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So ask yourself today- how is your relationship with food? Wherever you are on your journey, if it is restricted on what your body can tolerate, if it is learning to fuel and nourish your body, or if it is allowing yourself the enjoyment of eating a cookie, I see you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><summary type="html">When was the last time you asked yourself about your relationship with food?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1598536495/Blog/salsa-in-bowls_m9fi6v.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1598536495/Blog/salsa-in-bowls_m9fi6v.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">3 Ingredient Vegan Mac &amp;amp; Cheese</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Vegan-Mac-and-Cheese/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Ingredient Vegan Mac &amp; Cheese" /><published>2020-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Vegan-Mac-and-Cheese</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Vegan-Mac-and-Cheese/">&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday! On Fridays, I am generally worn out from cooking and want something easy. This vegan mac &amp;amp; cheese hits the spot. The best part is there is no soaking cashews or making your own sauce. All you have to do is purchase Good Foods plant based queso. I would bet you have the other two ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 Ingredient Vegan Mac &amp;amp; Cheese (Vegan, Paleo friendly)
Servings: 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 cup Good Foods Plant Based Queso&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tablespoons unsweetened almond milk (or any nut milk, may need more for thinning)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cups dry noodles (I like Banza chickpea shells, but any type works)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small saucepan over low heat, add plant based queso and almond milk, stirring to combine. Cook until the queso is warm. If desired, add more almond milk if you like a thinner sauce.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook noodles according to packaging instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour sauce over noodles and serve with fresh ground pepper and hot sauce.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="vegan" /><category term="easy" /><summary type="html">Happy Friday! On Fridays, I am generally worn out from cooking and want something easy. This vegan mac &amp;amp; cheese hits the spot. The best part is there is no soaking cashews or making your own sauce. All you have to do is purchase Good Foods plant based queso. I would bet you have the other two ingredients.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1598537987/Blog/3-ingredient-mac-cheese_yekfpa.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/rockmonkey/image/upload/v1598537987/Blog/3-ingredient-mac-cheese_yekfpa.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>