<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-15T09:18:54-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Health, Healing, and Hope (H3)</title><subtitle>Join me as I catalog my journey of the peaks and valleys of health, healing, and hope (H3 with Laura). I want to share some of my favorite paleo, gluten free, refined sugar-free, and egg free recipes. I hope to share my thoughts on health related topics and provide meaningful tips.</subtitle><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><entry><title type="html">Skin Care Reboot</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/14/Tues-Skin-Care-Reboot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Skin Care Reboot" /><published>2020-07-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/14/Tues-Skin-Care-Reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/14/Tues-Skin-Care-Reboot/">&lt;p&gt;As many of you already know, I was diagnosed with Rosacea fulminans a little over a month ago. It came up out of the blue but luckily with the help of my dermatologist, it cleared up within a couple weeks and has not recurred since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I slacked skin care and never even washed my face until a few years ago. With age and then this recent diagnosis I wanted to make changes recommended by my
dermatologist to my skin care routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few years, I used products by Rodan and Fields. However, these last two weeks, I used the products shown in the picture and already noticed a vast improvement in my skin.
These products were specifically recommended by my dermatologist based on skin and medical history. I am not saying this is what is right for everyone because there is not one size fits all when it comes to skin. What works for me, may not work for you and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would highly recommend consulting with a dermatologist to build out a tailored approach for your specific skin. For me, the tailored approach by the dermatologist means that I no longer buy a host of products (R&amp;amp;F, Ulta, BeautyCounter, etc) thus saving money and ultimately have better results for my specific skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rosacea fulminans was actually believed to result from a high amount of vitamin B I was taking, without doctor approval. I did not know too much of a B vitamin could cause a reaction that it did with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a long story short, I believe in balance and I believe in taking a holistic approach to medicine. I would not be where I am today health wise without a holistic approach to health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help heal my #rosaceafulminans, I did take an antibiotic and use a steroid cream but I also stayed away from high inflammatory foods, sun and tried to monitor my stress. It took both to get it to clear up just like it has taken both to help heal my adrenal fatigue, hypothyroidism, irritable bowel syndrome, fibromyalgia, parasites, depression and, anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of our bodies are different and the road to health, healing, and hope may not look the same but I am here sharing my journey with you in hopes that it empowers and inspires you to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><summary type="html">As many of you already know, I was diagnosed with Rosacea fulminans a little over a month ago. It came up out of the blue but luckily with the help of my dermatologist, it cleared up within a couple weeks and has not recurred since.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/skin-care-products_gt5xgn.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/skin-care-products_gt5xgn.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Feta &amp;amp; Kale Turkey Burgers</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/10/Feta-Kale-Turkey-Burgers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Feta &amp; Kale Turkey Burgers" /><published>2020-07-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/10/Feta-Kale-Turkey-Burgers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/10/Feta-Kale-Turkey-Burgers/">&lt;p&gt;I love a good turkey burger over a bed of lettuce. I made this on a whim and loved it! It is very easy and versatile which makes for a perfect weeknight meal. I used rice crumbs in this recipe but if you want to keep it grain free just swap it for almond flour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-pound ground turkey meat (85 percent 15 percent fat)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup diced yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup rice crumbs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup finely chopped kale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup feta (can add more or skip)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ tablespoons ketchup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon Dijon mustard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon primal BBQ seasoning (optional)
Dash of salt &amp;amp; pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop Kale and yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients and mix well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Form into burger patties (should make around 5)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat skillet over medium high heat with avocado oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add burger patties to hot skillet and cook on each side for 4-5minutes with lid on until cooked through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><summary type="html">I love a good turkey burger over a bed of lettuce. I made this on a whim and loved it! It is very easy and versatile which makes for a perfect weeknight meal. I used rice crumbs in this recipe but if you want to keep it grain free just swap it for almond flour.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/feta-kale-turkey-burgers_veerlg.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/feta-kale-turkey-burgers_veerlg.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting off Sugar</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/09/Getting-Off-Sugar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting off Sugar" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/09/Getting-Off-Sugar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/09/Getting-Off-Sugar/">&lt;p&gt;Did you know that sugar is 8 times more addictive than cocaine? Sugar is said to be the root cause of our obesity epidemic and chronic diseases. Dr. Mark Hyman says, “Being addicted to sugar and flour is not an emotional eating disorder. It’s a biological disorder, driven by hormones and neurotransmitters that fuel sugar and carb cravings — leading to uncontrolled overeating”.
Here are some of my tips to getting off of sugar, or lowering your intake of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get off sugar for 10 days- there are lots of sugar detox plans out there and getting off sugar cold turkey is really the only thing we can do to kick the addiction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read ingredients- educate yourself on what you are putting into your body. This will not only be eye opening but you will discover which brands do not have added sugar or preservatives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop drinking sugar- a 16oz white chocolate mocha has 53 grams of sugar. Even real fruit juice has on average 24 grams of sugar. Ditch the orange juice and eat the orange.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare for emergencies- pack snacks, in your purse, in a drawer at your office, or in your fridge. That way if you get hungry or find yourself reaching for the donuts your coworker brought in, you have a choice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a piece of fruit- if you find yourself craving sugar, cut up a peach or an apple. Add a fat, like almond butter to help keep you full and balance your blood sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><summary type="html">Did you know that sugar is 8 times more addictive than cocaine? Sugar is said to be the root cause of our obesity epidemic and chronic diseases. Dr. Mark Hyman says, “Being addicted to sugar and flour is not an emotional eating disorder. It’s a biological disorder, driven by hormones and neurotransmitters that fuel sugar and carb cravings — leading to uncontrolled overeating”. Here are some of my tips to getting off of sugar, or lowering your intake of it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Differences Between Refined vs. Natural Sugar</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/07/Tues-Refined-vs-Natural-Sugar/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Differences Between Refined vs. Natural Sugar" /><published>2020-07-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/07/Tues-Refined-vs-Natural-Sugar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/07/Tues-Refined-vs-Natural-Sugar/">&lt;p&gt;Last week, I shared a little bit about refined sugar and reasons why I avoid it. Today, I wanted to talk about better alternatives to refined sugar and share why they are better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some types of natural sugar include raw honey, pure maple syrup, blackstrap molasses, and coconut sugar. The main difference is these occur in their natural form (not refined or processed) and have some beneficial health properties. For example, honey contains high vitamin and mineral contents as well as antimicrobial benefits, which is why it has been known as a healing food for quite some time. Coconut sugar has nutrients like zinc, calcium, potassium and iron. Refined sugar does not have any nutrients, which is why it is often referred to as empty calories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural sugar has a lower glycemic effect, which means it does not cause as high of a rise in blood sugar as refined sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, just because natural sugar is better, does not necessarily mean we should live off of it. Natural sugar is still sugar and should be consumed modestly. Although making the swap from refined to natural is a great choice, you may need to get off sugar entirely to kill the addiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, I am at a point in my health journey where I am able to enjoy treats with natural sugar, this was not always the case. There were times when I had to be off all added sugar and even limit the amount of fruit I consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the food we consume can/will vary based on what our bodies are needing. What is your body needing? Do you desire to break the addiction of sugar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, I am going to share some tips and steps we can take to limit our consumption of sugar and why getting off sugar for even a week may be the step your body needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><summary type="html">Last week, I shared a little bit about refined sugar and reasons why I avoid it. Today, I wanted to talk about better alternatives to refined sugar and share why they are better.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/sugar-types_va8lcq.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/sugar-types_va8lcq.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fudgy Brownies</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/03/Fudgy-Brownies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fudgy Brownies" /><published>2020-07-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/03/Fudgy-Brownies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/03/Fudgy-Brownies/">&lt;p&gt;I hope you guys are having a great weekend so far! I am sharing one of my all-time favorite recipes- fudgy brownies with crispy edges, SO good. If you need an easy and delicious dessert for the holiday weekend, look no further. It is Gluten Free, paleo, egg-free and refined-sugar-free but I promise no one will be able to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fudgy Brownies (paleo &amp;amp; vegan friendly)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 16 brownies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons ground flaxseed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup boiling water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 softened grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup pure maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons pure vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup almond flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup coco powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼- ½ cup paleo chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350F and place parchment paper in an 8 by 8 square pan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 4 tablespoons ground flaxseed and ½ cup boiling water and let sit for 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the softened butter, flax eggs, coconut sugar, maple syrup and vanilla extract to a bowl and mix until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the almond flour, coco powder, baking soda &amp;amp; sea salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in chocolate chips.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place batter in prepared pan and spread evenly (the batter will be sticky).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 35-40 minutes (mine take 36-37) or until edges are crispy and top with flacked sea salt if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let cool completely. Store at room temperature for a day and then transfer to the fridge.
** To make vegan I would substitute palm shortening or Earth Balance stick butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="desserts" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="paleo" /><summary type="html">I hope you guys are having a great weekend so far! I am sharing one of my all-time favorite recipes- fudgy brownies with crispy edges, SO good. If you need an easy and delicious dessert for the holiday weekend, look no further. It is Gluten Free, paleo, egg-free and refined-sugar-free but I promise no one will be able to tell.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/fudgy-brownie_nupsnx.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/fudgy-brownie_nupsnx.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">All About Sugar</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/01/Tues-Sugar-Everywhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All About Sugar" /><published>2020-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/01/Tues-Sugar-Everywhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/07/01/Tues-Sugar-Everywhere/">&lt;p&gt;Did you know there were so many types of sugar? What happens when you see a cookie or your favorite candy? Have you stopped to notice how your tongue salivates, or self control goes out the window?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sugar is literally a drug for our bodies. When we eat sugar, our bodies release something called dopamine which basically means sugar activates pleasure. The same response happens with cocaine, heroin, or any addictive drug. This is why it can be so hard to stop eating sugar or eat it in moderation. We become powerless to our brains’ hardwired response to seek out pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is sugar addictive but it is also said to cause weight gain, increasing risk of heart disease, acne, type 2 diabetes, cancer, depression, cellular ageing, obesity, can lead to a fatty liver, and chronic diseases. Those are just a few examples of what sugar can do to our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sugar can be a sneaky ingredient because it goes by hundreds of names as listed about. It can be found in our tomato sauces, salad dressings, meats (like bacon and turkey meat), yogurt, bread, beverages, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know sugar is not necessarily good for our bodies. Now what? My first recommendation is to take time to go through your fridge, freezer, pantry and read the labels. I bet you will be surprised with how many of them have sugar in them. Also, familiarize yourself with all the different names of sugar.  At the store, plan extra time to read the labels so you can buy the tomato sauce that does not have added sugar. Sugar is not created equally and certain types are far better than others (something I will cover at a later date). It was enlightening to see how much and where sugar shows up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Tip Thursday, I am going to share some more tips on what we can do to kick the sugar carvings, and lessen the amount we consume. If you want to read more about the effects of sugar on our bodies, I recommend looking up Dr. Mark Hyman. He has been a source of information for me as I have made lifestyle changes over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, change does not happen overnight so do not shame or overwhelm yourself. Start with educating yourself, and making a realistic plan. My lifestyle has not become what it is in a day, or even a year. It is an ongoing journey.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><summary type="html">Did you know there were so many types of sugar? What happens when you see a cookie or your favorite candy? Have you stopped to notice how your tongue salivates, or self control goes out the window?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/wordcloud_sugar_tkr6xh.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/wordcloud_sugar_tkr6xh.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Funfetti Cake</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/26/Funfetti-Cake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Funfetti Cake" /><published>2020-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/26/Funfetti-Cake</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/26/Funfetti-Cake/">&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of Funfetti cake so I wanted to make it for my birthday this year. However, don’t wait until your birthday to make this. We can always find a reason to celebrate right?
This recipe is easy and can be paleo and vegan with a few tweaks. I cannot find paleo sprinkles, so unfortunately those have refined sugar but they are dye free. Also, if you are vegan, just use vegan butter instead of grass-fed. If possible use a stick butter and not the spreadable kind. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FUNFETTI CAKE (PALEO &amp;amp; VEGAN FRIENDLY)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cake:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons ground flaxseed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 tablespoons boiling water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup apple sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup melted coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Simple Mills vanilla cake mix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frosting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 Tablespoons grass-fed butter softened (can also use vegan butter)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup + 2 tablespoons vegan cashew cream cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup + 3 tablespoons paleo powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sprinkles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions
Cake:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 325F and grease 2 round 8 x 8 pans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 2 tablespoons ground flaxseed and 5 tablespoons cup boiling water and let sit for 15- 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add flax eggs, apple sauce, melted coconut oil, water, and vanilla to a bowl and stir until it is mixed together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in the cake mix and mix until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in the sprinkles (add as many or as little as you want).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place batter in prepared pans and spread evenly in both.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 30-35 minutes (baking instructions on the box).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let cool completely for 10 minutes and then transfer to a cooling rack.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait until the cake is completely cooled before icing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frosting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add butter, cashew cream cheese, and powdered sugar into a bowl and mix until combined (I used a hand mixer).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fold in sprinkles. Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="vegan" /><category term="easy" /><category term="desserts" /><summary type="html">I am a big fan of Funfetti cake so I wanted to make it for my birthday this year. However, don’t wait until your birthday to make this. We can always find a reason to celebrate right? This recipe is easy and can be paleo and vegan with a few tweaks. I cannot find paleo sprinkles, so unfortunately those have refined sugar but they are dye free. Also, if you are vegan, just use vegan butter instead of grass-fed. If possible use a stick butter and not the spreadable kind. Enjoy!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/funfetti-cake_hnjcrr.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/funfetti-cake_hnjcrr.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sugar Types</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/25/Thurs-Birthday-Cake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sugar Types" /><published>2020-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/25/Thurs-Birthday-Cake</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/25/Thurs-Birthday-Cake/">&lt;p&gt;Easy &amp;amp; Healthier Birthday Cake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I am sharing tips on how to make an easy and healthy (ier) birthday cake. My first tip is make your own powdered sugar. Store bought powdered sugar is filled with refined sugar and cornstarch. My powdered sugar is made with pure maple sugar and a little bit of arrowroot. I promise it is even better than store bought both tastewise, and healthwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use coconut sugar. I gravitate towards maple sugar because it is lighter in color with a really great flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is simple and keeps in the panty. All you need is 1 cup maple sugar and 2 teaspoons arrowroot. Add them blender and blend until it turns into a powder.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="desserts" /><summary type="html">Easy &amp;amp; Healthier Birthday Cake</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/icing_oglhhz.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/icing_oglhhz.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mom’s Chicken Salad</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/23/Chicken-Salad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mom's Chicken Salad" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/23/Chicken-Salad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/06/23/Chicken-Salad/">&lt;p&gt;Instead of #topictuesday today, I thought I would share an easy and perfect summer recipe. I always loved my Mom’s chicken salad and knew I needed to make my own version. I love to eat it over greens, with crackers, or with some toasted bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom’s Chicken Salad (paleo, egg free)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 chicken breasts shredded (or can use rotisserie)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup @followyourheart mayonnaise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup chopped grapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup chopped walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup chopped celery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ground pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make the chicken, add water to the bottom of your crockpot and place chicken in the water. Sprinkle with salt and pepper and cook on high for 2-3 hours or low until chicken is cooked all the way through.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take chicken out and shred.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all the ingredients into a bowl and stir until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep in an airtight container in the refrigerator.
***** I do not like a ton of mayo, so add as little or as much as you like. If you do not have grapes, I also love chopped apple and/or Craisins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="vegan" /><category term="easy" /><summary type="html">Instead of #topictuesday today, I thought I would share an easy and perfect summer recipe. I always loved my Mom’s chicken salad and knew I needed to make my own version. I love to eat it over greens, with crackers, or with some toasted bread.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/chicken-salad_eedpwq.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/chicken-salad_eedpwq.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gluten Free Cinnamon Toast Crunch</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/29/Cinnamon-Toast-Crunch-Gluten-Free/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gluten Free Cinnamon Toast Crunch" /><published>2020-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/29/Cinnamon-Toast-Crunch-Gluten-Free</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/29/Cinnamon-Toast-Crunch-Gluten-Free/">&lt;p&gt;I made @halfbakedharvest Cinnamon Toast Crunch recipe and had to make a glutenfree and refinedsugarfree one. I hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 3 cups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tablespoon cinnamon plus ¼ teaspoon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup maple sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ¼ cups King Arthur All Purpose Gluten free flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 tablespoons grass-fed butter (cut into cubes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup cold water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 tablespoons melted grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the maple sugar and ½ tablespoon on cinnamon in a small bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the food processor, combine the gluten free flour, 1/3 teaspoon cinnamon, fine sea salt and chopped butter. Pulse until it starts to clump together. Then add the vanilla and 1 tablespoon of cold water at a time. Keep adding the water until the dough comes together. Note, the dough will be sticky.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flour a piece of parchment paper and form the dough into a ball (I had to add a little bit of flour to the dough). Add in 1 tablespoon of the cinnamon sugar mixture and fold into dough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next roll out dough until it is about 1/8 inch thick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brush melted butter all over the dough and sprinkle the cinnamon sugar mixture evenly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut into ½ inch squares.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 14 minutes. Remove from oven and separate the squares and flip them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for an additional 4-8 minutes or until golden brown. Let them cool on a wire rack and store in an airtight container for up to one week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** My dough was too sticky to separate the squares before putting them in the oven, that is why I say do it after it has baked a while. Also, if you can flip your dough you can coat both sides with butter and cinnamon sugar (just use half cinnamon sugar mixture on each side).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="vegan" /><category term="easy" /><summary type="html">I made @halfbakedharvest Cinnamon Toast Crunch recipe and had to make a glutenfree and refinedsugarfree one. I hope you enjoy!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/cinnamon-toast-crunch_goc2mi.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/cinnamon-toast-crunch_goc2mi.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>