<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-24T14:10:57-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Health, Healing, and Hope (H3)</title><subtitle>Join me as I catalog my journey of the peaks and valleys of health, healing, and hope (H3 with Laura). I want to share some of my favorite paleo, gluten free, refined sugar-free, and egg free recipes. I hope to share my thoughts on health related topics and provide meaningful tips.</subtitle><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><entry><title type="html">Mocha Sauce</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/23/Refined-Sugar-Free-Mocha-Sauce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mocha Sauce" /><published>2020-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/23/Refined-Sugar-Free-Mocha-Sauce</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/23/Refined-Sugar-Free-Mocha-Sauce/">&lt;p&gt;If you missed it, I am a coffee lover. When I decided to give up refined sugar, it made going to a coffee shop a little harder. Sugar is a sneaky ingredient and is in all the fun drinks like an iced mocha!
I decided it was time to create my own mocha sauce. Let me tell you: it will make you not miss Starbucks at all. Enjoy an iced mocha with all the yumminess but without the sugar crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 1 ½ cups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup filtered water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup unsweetened coco powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup pure maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoons cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients except vanilla extract in a sauce pan over medium high heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisking constantly, let cook for around 5 minutes or until sauce has thickened.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in the vanilla extract and allow to cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store in an airtight container in the fridge for up to 2 weeks or in freezer for up to 3 months.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy in coffee, on ice cream or whatever your heart desires!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="vegan" /><summary type="html">If you missed it, I am a coffee lover. When I decided to give up refined sugar, it made going to a coffee shop a little harder. Sugar is a sneaky ingredient and is in all the fun drinks like an iced mocha! I decided it was time to create my own mocha sauce. Let me tell you: it will make you not miss Starbucks at all. Enjoy an iced mocha with all the yumminess but without the sugar crash.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/mocha-sauce_tc6xlu.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/mocha-sauce_tc6xlu.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (Resounding Yes)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/22/Thurs-Resounding-Yes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (Resounding Yes)" /><published>2020-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/22/Thurs-Resounding-Yes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/22/Thurs-Resounding-Yes/">&lt;p&gt;For #topictueaday, I shared about my goal of saying no is to create opportunity to spend my time on things I value most in life. It took me years to feel confident in saying no if it is not an unmistakable yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tip Thursday is all about small changes with potential to make a significant impact down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we practically live this out? I would first identify what brings you joy. Is it family time, painting, or getting coffee with a particular friend? Then identify what your schedule looked like before this pandemic. Are there things, activities, clubs, maybe even relationships you could not step back into?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we say no to and how we actively walk that out is going to be different for all of us. We can all evaluate our hearts and lives to better understand what is life giving and what may be life sucking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journal, talk to your partner or a good friend and ask what they think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next advice is just to start saying no. Sounds easy right? If an invitation arises and you can feel yourself becoming stressed, bummed, or not wanting to go, then say no. See how it feels to say no and then how you feel after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would start small. I am not advising to quit your job because it does not bring you passion. Maybe will that at some point. I would say start saying no to small things and start saying yes to the things bringing joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where are you going to start? What area in your life do you already know is a no? What opportunities will arise where you can sound a resounding yes to and say no to another?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">For #topictueaday, I shared about my goal of saying no is to create opportunity to spend my time on things I value most in life. It took me years to feel confident in saying no if it is not an unmistakable yes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/cheers-resounding-yes_mv64y1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/cheers-resounding-yes_mv64y1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (Resounding Yes)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/19/Letting-Go-Resounding-Yes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (Resounding Yes)" /><published>2020-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/19/Letting-Go-Resounding-Yes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/19/Letting-Go-Resounding-Yes/">&lt;p&gt;A pattern in of my life is my desire to please others. I tend to busy myself with things, people, activities and I think the root of it comes from wanting to please others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my journey required learning how to say no. I required rest in order for me to heal which meant I could not do and be the person everyone wanted me to be. I definitely grieved this. I needed to relearn who I was and what my motives were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, most of us are at home and busyness ground to a complete halt. We are spending more time with our families, in the kitchen and maybe even in our yards. Although we are in a hard and challenging season, time is a new gift. Time creates opportunity to enjoy your house, the outdoors, and time with your family. All of this made me realize I need to carry over some of this time when life starts going again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard people say I want things to go back to normal but I wonder how many of us are going to create a new normal. I want my new normal to be able to enjoy a coffee with a friend again or picking out flowers for our front porch but I also want it to have night with nothing on the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite people to follow is @livingwithlandryn and she outlined it as only saying yes to the things bringing the utmost joy. If it is not a resounding yes, it is a no. As we step back into life and old routines ask yourself before responding to an email, text or invitation is this an unmistakable yes? Is this something I am stoked and excited to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I talked about #minimalism - the intentional promotion of the things I most value in life by removing anything that distracts me from it. I believe it goes deeper than stuff but to our schedules and lives. The goal is by saying no I am creating the opportunity to spend my time on the things I value most in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you mark as a no to allow to the time, mental and emotion space to pursue your greatest desires and passions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture is from picking strawberries - an example of an unmistakable yes for me. Who knows if in “normal life” I would make the time to pick strawberries, soak them, dry them and then cut them to place in the freezer or fridge. It was so fun, and even though preparing them took longer, I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #tipthursday, I will share some practical ways on how we can understand our unmistakable yes(s) and what we can do to prepare as life starts to get busy again.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">A pattern in of my life is my desire to please others. I tend to busy myself with things, people, activities and I think the root of it comes from wanting to please others.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/strawberry-picking_uaqecl.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/strawberry-picking_uaqecl.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Fire Roasted Salsa</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/15/Fire-Roasted-Salsa-Applewood/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fire Roasted Salsa" /><published>2020-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/15/Fire-Roasted-Salsa-Applewood</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/15/Fire-Roasted-Salsa-Applewood/">&lt;p&gt;This recipe is easy to do and always a crowd pleaser. It is a fantastic way to up your taco game and avoid store bought salsa loaded with extra ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 small/medium sized roma tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 habaneros&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 jalapenos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 sliced red pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lime juiced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handful of cilantro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start grill and preheat to 350-400F (We use apple wood chips to give a complementary smoke flavor)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice and deseed the habaneros, jalapenos, red pepper (Pro tip – put on latex/nitrile gloves for handling peppers)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop onion in half and then in quarters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add roma tomatoes, sliced habaneros, jalapenos, red pepper and onion onto a grill safe pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grill at indirect heat at 350-400F until the red pepper edges are slighting brown / black and the skin of the tomatoes should start to peel off&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove skin from the Roma tomatoes and add all the ingredients from the grill to a food processor. Add fresh lime juice, cilantro and sea salt and pulse until it has reached your desired consistency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store in an airtight container and refrigerate salsa for at least 2 hours before serving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt; If you like spicy salsa you can always add another jalapeno or habanero and/or avoid deseed jalapenos/habaneros&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="snacks" /><category term="vegetables" /><summary type="html">This recipe is easy to do and always a crowd pleaser. It is a fantastic way to up your taco game and avoid store bought salsa loaded with extra ingredients.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/fire-roasted-salsa-chips_s0ayrs.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/fire-roasted-salsa-chips_s0ayrs.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (Exercise for Weightloss)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/14/Letting-Go-of-Exercise-for-Weightloss/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (Exercise for Weightloss)" /><published>2020-05-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/14/Letting-Go-of-Exercise-for-Weightloss</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/14/Letting-Go-of-Exercise-for-Weightloss/">&lt;p&gt;For #topictuesday, I shared about letting go of exercising for weight loss and exercise for my overall wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way I improved my wellbeing was by avoiding the scale. I used to go on it two/three times per week. Now, I only went on it once the last three/four months. Muscle weighs more than fat. When I start to exercise, specifically weightlifting, I gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A normal scale does not tell you if you gained muscle or not. One thing I have found helpful is use the scale at my doctor’s office. It measures your muscle per leg, arms, etc., and also computes overall fat and muscle percentages. It allows me to see my progress and my overall health compared to a number on a scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may sound easier than it is but listening to my body resulted in mindset shift. My body never lies. Yet somehow when my body tells me it is tired and needs to slow down I like to push it further. I do this with exercise but used to do it with food and alcohol. If I did not sleep well and my body was begging for rest, I indulged in things like caffeine and sugar to help give me a boost. On days of stress and feeling overwhelmed, I consumed too many glasses of alcohol to make it go away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to my body in regards to exercise can look different depending on the day. It can be resting on a day I planned to run. It can also be getting off the couch when I want to veg out. This morning on my run I wanted to run six miles, but I was running faster than normal and by mile four I knew my body was asking me to slow down. I decided to walk for a minute and then ran again. I ran another mile when I realized I did not need to push my body any harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few helpful ways to change my perspective when it comes to exercise but I am not perfect. There are still days I want to jump on the scale and force myself to go just a little heavier or a little longer. I gently remind myself of my overall goal: health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the things you can practically do to help change your perspective on exercising for wellbeing?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="letting-go" /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html">For #topictuesday, I shared about letting go of exercising for weight loss and exercise for my overall wellbeing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/gps-watch-data_gqp530.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/gps-watch-data_gqp530.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (Exercise for Weightloss)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/12/Letting-Go-Series-Exercise-Weightloss/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (Exercise for Weightloss)" /><published>2020-05-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/12/Letting-Go-Series-Exercise-Weightloss</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/12/Letting-Go-Series-Exercise-Weightloss/">&lt;p&gt;There have been times in my life where I exercised simply to lose weight. The harder I worked in the gym, the more I hoped to see come off the scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The irony for me was the harder I worked out the more weight I gained and the less I worked out the more weight I lost. I know it is not the case for everyone. During the time where I would push my body to the limits by going to the gym a couple hours a day almost every day, I pushed it too far and did not listening to what my body was saying. I needed rest to recover and I never allowed my body the rest. Sadly, I fixated on seeing my number on the scale go down, and I did not care to notice how bad I hurt my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I hit the point where I could not do anything and allowed my body to rest and heal, I began to lose the weight. I know my story is probably unlike most but I do think most can relate. Are you exercising to lose weight?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I have found the important of exercise for my health, both physically and mentally. It is easy to feel let down after working hard at the gym (or in this case my garage) and not seeing the desired results. Exercise produces results beyond what we can see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular exercise results in profound positive impacts on depression, anxiety, ADHD, stress and can improve memory, boost overall mood and much more. For me, regular exercise gives a sense of wellbeing. I have more energy, more confidence, I sleep better at night and overall, and I just feel better about myself and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing all that, why is it still so easy to feel frustrated and unmotivated as soon as I step on the scale? On #tipthursday, I am going to share how I battled the feelings and emotions and share ways which helped me let go of exercising for weight loss. I flipped the mindset and started exercising for my wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge is to exercise for wellbeing. Changing our mindset from exercising strictly to lose weight to exercising because it is good for our body, soul, and mind. I am not saying a goal to lose weight is bad but I think we will see more positive results both mentally, emotionally, and physically if we exercise for our wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about some of the positive affects you have seen from exercise not related to weight or physical results. Maybe you found a community or ground of friends. Maybe it brought self-confidence. Maybe it allowed you to enjoy a hike with your family. Whatever it is, rest in those positive effects and gratitude for your body - not for what it could be, or you hope it to be but for what it is right now and all it has done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="letting-go" /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html">There have been times in my life where I exercised simply to lose weight. The harder I worked in the gym, the more I hoped to see come off the scale.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/Laura-Barbell_ss7qp2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/Laura-Barbell_ss7qp2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Strawberry Pecan Crisp</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/08/Strawberry-Pecan-Crisp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strawberry Pecan Crisp" /><published>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/08/Strawberry-Pecan-Crisp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/08/Strawberry-Pecan-Crisp/">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we went to a farm and picked strawberries so I obviously had to make a strawberry crisp. It turned out so yummy, I could not wait to share it with you! If you do not have strawberries on hand, no worries as any berries will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strawberry Filling
Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 ½ cup chopped strawberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup honey (or maple syrup)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ tablespoons arrowroot powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tablespoons lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topping&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup gluten free oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 tablespoons softened grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup almond flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup chopped pecans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350 F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chopped strawberries, honey, arrowroot, lemon juice and cinnamon to a 9 by 9 square pan and stir until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium size bowl stir together the oats, almond flour, pecans, coconut sugar, vanilla extract and salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in softened butter and stir until combined (can use a hand mixer but I always use my hands).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the topping mixture to the strawberry filling and spread it out evenly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 40-45 minutes or until the filling is bubbling around the edges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy with vanilla ice cream!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt; If using frozen strawberries, let them thaw completely.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="desserts" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="nuts" /><summary type="html">Last weekend we went to a farm and picked strawberries so I obviously had to make a strawberry crisp. It turned out so yummy, I could not wait to share it with you! If you do not have strawberries on hand, no worries as any berries will work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/strawberry-pecan-crisp_oq2c77.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/strawberry-pecan-crisp_oq2c77.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (Living Minimally)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/05/Tues-Letting-Go-of-Stuff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (Living Minimally)" /><published>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/05/Tues-Letting-Go-of-Stuff</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/05/Tues-Letting-Go-of-Stuff/">&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the “Letting Go” series, one of the areas I felt I needed to let go of is unused stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared a little about how important keeping a clean house is for me. During our time at home in these unusual times, we decided to go through everything we own. Living minimally has always sparked my interest but not something I fully understood or practiced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We listened to a podcast with a guest named Joshua Becker and he defined minimalism as “The intentional promotion of the things I most value in life by removing anything that distracts me from it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shared the goal of minimalism is not about owning the fewest stuff but about pursuing our greatest values and desires with more passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed to figure out what we valued most. For us, it is about experience, the time and financial freedom to do so. We realized we were spending time and money taking care of our stuff, when we would rather be experiencing, traveling, hiking, and having friends over. For example, there is stuff we moved from AK to OK to TN where we did not even open the box. We spent time figuring out where to store those boxes in each residence and money moving them across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one ever looks back on their life thankful for their stuff or the things they bought. I want to make sure that I am able to passionately pursue my hobbies and desires to the fullest. For us, it means removing the things we do not use and practice mindfulness when we purchase something. It is about quality not quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not mean I only have 10 pieces of clothing or have nothing on the walls. I am choosing to be intentional about what we keep in our house and what we purchase. I free up mental space if I can walk into my closet and know all the items fit and I will wear them. Ultimately, I want to spend my free time exploring and experiencing. It is mentally and physically taxing to clean, organize, maintain, and tend to things which do not advance my goal of an experience driven lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #tipthursday, I am going to share how we practically are doing this. It is not something done in a week. It can take months. It is also not a one and done but a lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there anything you can let go of? Are there clothes, decorations, or kitchen items taking up space physically but also emotionally and mentally? What are your greatest values and desires? Are you setting yourself up for success by creating time, space and energy in order to pursue them?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="letting-go" /><category term="cleaning" /><category term="mindfulness" /><summary type="html">Continuing with the “Letting Go” series, one of the areas I felt I needed to let go of is unused stuff.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/living-minimally_c2avap.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/living-minimally_c2avap.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (I Am Enough - Part 2)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/30/Thurs-I-Am-Enough-Cont/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (I Am Enough - Part 2)" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/30/Thurs-I-Am-Enough-Cont</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/30/Thurs-I-Am-Enough-Cont/">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I shared about speaking truth into my life and letting go of the lies. One of the biggest lies I allowed in is that I am not enough. If you want to read more about how and why head to my &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough&quot;&gt;#topictuesday post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in letting go of anything is acknowledgment. What is the next step? How do I practically let go of that lie and live in the truth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it is making sure I am feeding my body, soul and spirit with truth and love. Personally, I wake up and spend time in God’s Word. It grounds me in truth and allows time for reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest in the truth and free the lies. It is a simple concept but requires an arduous effort to master. Do you recognize when shame starts to creep in? It is help to analyze what you are listening to and where your thoughts are taking you. Evaluate your actions and then act. Do not rest in shame, or lies. Shift your mindset and perspective into truth. It may mean taking a minute to breath or verbalize aloud positive self-talk. It may mean reaching out to your spouse or loved one and asking them to pray for you or speak into the lie or situation. It may also mean taking time and reflecting. Anchoring your identity, purpose, and relationships in the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk a lot about understanding our why. Why do I feel like I am not enough? Why have I allowed shame to shape so much of my life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be vulnerable. Open up those closets you keep shut. Open up to yourself, to a friend, or your partner. Vulnerability creates vulnerability. It brings light and truth into the darkness and lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge to you is rest in the truth and free the lies. How we do that may look different for all of us. What are some of the ways you can live in the truth and free the lies?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">On Tuesday, I shared about speaking truth into my life and letting go of the lies. One of the biggest lies I allowed in is that I am not enough. If you want to read more about how and why head to my #topictuesday post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (I Am Enough)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (I Am Enough)" /><published>2020-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough/">&lt;p&gt;As I spent time these last few weeks asking myself what I need to let go of, the notion of “Not feeling like I am enough” seems to be at forefront of my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, I have been a number of sizes in my life. For so long, I believed when I lost the weight I would feel like I was enough. However, as I lost the weight, I began to realize the lie went much deeper than what showed on the outside. When I took my season of rest, it happened right after our wedding and moved away from all my family and friends. I went from loved ones around me, a full-time job, actively involved in a church, and going to school to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was heavier, I overcompensated by doing more and trying to being more. I busied myself by finding my worth in what I did. Fast forward to my season of rest where I started losing weight without trying but I had no one. No friends, no schedule, and no activities. As I felt like I was not enough in one area, I tried extra hard in the another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now looking back on both seasons and living my current one, where I am healthy, I still struggle with not being enough. Here I am healthy but I am not working. I have been married for four years but do not have children. How do I answer when someone asks what I do? I feel guilty because I know it is a privilege to not work and focus on my health but it can also be extremely lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circumstances change. They always will. Do I put my worth in my circumstances? In what I am doing today? In what I look like today? If I did, it would be fleeting. I would not be setting myself up for success but rather disappoint and failure because life is ever changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still learning, growing, processing and practicing how to control my thoughts around this by actively pushing out the lie and speaking truth. I am enough, not because of what I do or what I look like. I am enough because I believe I am enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple weeks, I am going to list more specific ways of letting go. I have to continue to rid my life of this lie and rest in the truth. For #tipthursday, I am going to share how I am practically doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What thought(s) or lie(s) do you need to be free of?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">As I spent time these last few weeks asking myself what I need to let go of, the notion of “Not feeling like I am enough” seems to be at forefront of my mind.</summary></entry></feed>