<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-16T10:28:21-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Health, Healing, and Hope (H3)</title><subtitle>Join me as I catalog my journey of the peaks and valleys of health, healing, and hope. I want to share some of my favorite paleo, gluten free, and egg free recipes. I hope to share my thoughts on health related topics and provide meaningful tips.</subtitle><author><name>Laura</name></author><entry><title type="html">Eat How You Want to Feel</title><link href="/2020/04/14/Eating-How-You-Want-To-Feel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eat How You Want to Feel" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/14/Eating-How-You-Want-To-Feel</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/14/Eating-How-You-Want-To-Feel.html">&lt;p&gt;Do you eat how you want to feel? Have you ever stopped to think about food in the context of feeling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you want to feel right now? Yes, we are at home more than usual. Yes, we are likely more scared, on edge, and trying to keep anxiety in check but how do you want to feel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would be remiss to put water and gasoline into your car and expect it to run smoothly at peak performance without issue. Garbage in. Garbage out. Why do I find myself always grabbing a bag of chips or ice cream and eating until it is gone? Eating a tub of ice cream may provide instant gratification but leaves an unpaid bill for later. Everything consumed affects mood, health, and relationships. If I want to feel energetic, clear minded, healthy, and active, I fuel my body with nutrient rich foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding our “why” is of the utmost important. Why do I want to eat healthy? Identify first how you want to feel (I assume we all want to feel exceptional) as it helps us understand our purpose and motivation moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am by no means saying I do not consume treats. Eat in moderation and accordance with how I want to feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, I am going to discussing snacking with mindfulness with the uptick in working from home. I will outline practical tips to put mindful snacking into motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you want to feel? Why do you want to feel that way? Are you eating how you want to feel? As you start to ask these questions, exercise grace with yourself (especially in the current circumstances).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><summary type="html">Do you eat how you want to feel? Have you ever stopped to think about food in the context of feeling?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/bowl-of-fruit.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/bowl-of-fruit.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Whipped Coffee</title><link href="/2020/04/11/Whipped-Coffee.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Whipped Coffee" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/11/Whipped-Coffee</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/11/Whipped-Coffee.html">&lt;p&gt;It is the weekend &amp;amp; the sun is shining which means whipped coffee is happening! I thought I would share how I make mine. There is less sugar and half the amount of coffee (I try to limit my caffeine) but you can always double it. I serve it cold but it can be made hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paleo Whipped Coffee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon instant coffee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon boiling water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malk vanilla unsweetened almond milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add instant coffee, boiling water, coconut sugar and cinnamon to a bowl and beat using a hand mixer(or whisk) until fluffy, light and soft peaks form&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add whipped coffee to ice and milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><summary type="html">It is the weekend &amp;amp; the sun is shining which means whipped coffee is happening! I thought I would share how I make mine. There is less sugar and half the amount of coffee (I try to limit my caffeine) but you can always double it. I serve it cold but it can be made hot.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/Whipped-Coffee.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/Whipped-Coffee.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Banana Bread</title><link href="/2020/04/10/Banana-Bread.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Banana Bread" /><published>2020-04-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/10/Banana-Bread</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/10/Banana-Bread.html">&lt;p&gt;It is Friday and we could all use a fun Saturday morning treat. This bread is delicious and will have your house smelling like a world class bakery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walnut Maple Banana Bread (paleo &amp;amp; egg free)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 flax egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 ripe bananas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup almond flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup tapioca flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup coconut flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 tablespoons grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ teaspoons baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toppings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hu Kitchen gems (Paleo Chocolate Chips)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chopped walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 1 tablespoons ground flaxseed and 2.5 tablespoons boiling water and let sit for 15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mash the bananas and add flax egg. Mix until combined&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the rest of the ingredients and stir until combined&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line your loaf pan with parchment paper and add your batter and toppings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 50 minutes to 1 hour (mine took 55 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool completely and store in the refrigerator for up to a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="favorite-recipes" /><summary type="html">It is Friday and we could all use a fun Saturday morning treat. This bread is delicious and will have your house smelling like a world class bakery.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/banana-bread.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/banana-bread.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Easter- Making the Holiday Special Under our Circumstances</title><link href="/2020/04/09/Thurs-Holidays.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Easter- Making the Holiday Special Under our Circumstances" /><published>2020-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/09/Thurs-Holidays</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/09/Thurs-Holidays.html">&lt;p&gt;Easter is on Sunday and we might be a little sad to deviate from normal traditions. Traditions like: going to church, enjoying a big meal with family and friends, or taking the kids to find Easter eggs. It all will look a little different this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself focusing too much on the “I wish”(s). I wish Easter could be like last year. I wish I could pick out a fun dress and go to church. I wish I could be with my family. I realized the negative state of mind served only to make matters worse. I decided to focus on the “I can”(s).  I can make the holiday special even under the current circumstances. I can still make a tasty meal. I can still share a meal with my family (via Facetime/Zoom/Skype/Other).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I challenge us to focus on what we can control rather than what we cannot control. I am still able to plan a fun menu for Easter dinner and find joy in it. I can still wear a dress as I watch church online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you do to make this holiday special? Can you hide Easter eggs (or just little treasures if you do not have eggs) around the house for your kids to find? Can you make a special dessert? Can you Facetime loved ones while you are sitting around your table?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us choose joy and hope and focus on the “I can”(s). A change in our mindset from “I wish” to “I can” may seem small. Small changes lead to big impacts down the road. Let us shift our mindset and perspective during this time to be grateful for the things we can control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still much you can control and much to celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="mindfulness" /><summary type="html">Easter is on Sunday and we might be a little sad to deviate from normal traditions. Traditions like: going to church, enjoying a big meal with family and friends, or taking the kids to find Easter eggs. It all will look a little different this year.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/dogwood-blooms.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/dogwood-blooms.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cleanliness</title><link href="/2020/04/07/Tues-Cleanliness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cleanliness" /><published>2020-04-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/07/Tues-Cleanliness</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/07/Tues-Cleanliness.html">&lt;p&gt;I am known for a clean house because for me it creates a space of peace and calmness. Right now, many of our homes seem to become dirtier quicker than usual with more meals eaten at home and with an increase in activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I like a deliberate and organized spot for everything. I regularly go through my clothes, drawers and cabinets to remove things I do not use. For me, it helps calm my anxiety and keep frustrations low. There are ample health benefits to living in a clean home to include lowering stress and fatigue, reducing allergy and asthma symptoms, and lessening the spread of germs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A study from Indiana University found people with clean houses were healthier people. The study described house cleanliness as a better predictor for physical health than neighborhood walkability. Another study out of Princeton University found clutter can make it more difficult to focus on a particular task. Specifically, they found the visual cortex can be overwhelmed by task-irrelevant objects, which made it harder to allocate attention and complete tasks efficiently. The National Sleep foundation reported people who make their beds every morning are 19 percent more likely to report getting a good night sleep and 75 percent of people say they achieve a better night sleep with clean sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we are all home more, this a exceptional opportunity for us to spend some time deep cleaning and organizing the clutter. There is a lot in our lives we cannot control but we can control the cleanliness of our homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our best home purchases was a robot vacuum. Let me tell you – it is one of the best purchases we made in our marriage. We run it just about every day (and it always picks up more dust than we could imagine). I always clean the kitchen and run the dishwasher after making dinner because starting the day with a clean kitchen is everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the year, I told myself I would go through every room, closet and drawer in the house. I generally do one a week with only a few bedrooms left. Deep cleaning can seem overwhelming to do it all at once so I break it up. I separate regular chores (like cleaning the bathrooms, vacuuming, laundry) from cleaning showers tubs, baseboards, fans, shutters etc. I tend to do my regular chores during the week and leave the other ones to about monthly. I try to keep the extra bedrooms to standard of cleanliness to allow friends to stop by on short notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this said, I do want to add to always be graceful with yourself. There have been times I did not complete what I hoped and that is alright. I think overall creating a standard of cleanliness helps set us up for success. Many of us are feeling more stressed and anxious than usual and cleanliness is one way that can help ease it. There is much we cannot control so let go of those areas and start focusing on what we can.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="cleaning" /><category term="cleaning-products" /><summary type="html">I am known for a clean house because for me it creates a space of peace and calmness. Right now, many of our homes seem to become dirtier quicker than usual with more meals eaten at home and with an increase in activity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/cleaning-products.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/cleaning-products.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Greek Chicken &amp;amp; Tzatziki</title><link href="/2020/04/03/Greek-Tzatziki.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greek Chicken &amp; Tzatziki" /><published>2020-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/03/Greek-Tzatziki</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/03/Greek-Tzatziki.html">&lt;p&gt;This recipe is very easy to do and the best part is you can prep it ahead of time (like nap time). Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tzatziki:&lt;/h4&gt;
                    &lt;ul class=&quot;alt&quot;&gt;

                    &lt;li&gt;1 cup Greek yogurt (can use nondairy or I have used lactose free sour cream) &lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;½ medium cucumber grated&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons white wine vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;1 tablespoon fresh dill (or ½ tablespoon dried dill)&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Dash of fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Marinade:&lt;/h4&gt;
                    &lt;ul class=&quot;alt&quot;&gt;

                    &lt;li&gt;1-pound chicken thigh&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;¼ cup fresh lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;¼ cup avocado oil&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;¼ cup Tzatziki&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon Italian seasoning&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;½ tablespoon minced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;li&gt;Salt &amp;amp; pepper&lt;/li&gt;
                    &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
  											&lt;ol&gt;
  												&lt;li&gt;Grate cucumber and drain through a fine strainer until liquid is removed&lt;/li&gt;
  												&lt;li&gt;Add all the Tzatziki ingredients in a bowl and mix until combined. Store in an airtight container for 3 days&lt;/li&gt;
  												&lt;li&gt;Add the chicken and marinade together in a bag and shake until the chicken is thoroughly coated in the marinade&lt;/li&gt;
  												&lt;li&gt;Marinade for 2-8 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  												&lt;li&gt;Grill chicken at indirect heat (400F/medium) until cooked through and serve with Tzatziki and serve with your favorite side (rice, cauliflower rice, or pita)&lt;/li&gt;
  											&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="ethnic" /><summary type="html">This recipe is very easy to do and the best part is you can prep it ahead of time (like nap time). Enjoy!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/Greek-Chicken-Bowls.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/Greek-Chicken-Bowls.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Try Something New</title><link href="/2020/04/02/Thurs-Try-Something-New.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Try Something New" /><published>2020-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/04/02/Thurs-Try-Something-New</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/04/02/Thurs-Try-Something-New.html">&lt;p&gt;We all have more time on our hands then we know what to do with. I am choosing to look at this time as a gift and prioritize things I wanted to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tip Thursdays are about making small changes for a significant impact down the road. Trying something new does not have to be huge. It can be a small change, or a small step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to stay away from social media and my phone when I first wake up. Right now, my goal is for the first hour. Instead of waking up and immediately turning over in bed to grab my phone, I am taking the time to check in with myself. I am focusing on my breath and spending time praying. After, I generally go and make my celery juice, empty the dishwasher, and spend time journaling, reading, praying and listening to worship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us all use this time we have to try some new things or create new practices and habits. I would love to hear some of the things you are trying&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="social-media" /><category term="mindfulness" /><summary type="html">We all have more time on our hands then we know what to do with. I am choosing to look at this time as a gift and prioritize things I wanted to try.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anxiety</title><link href="/2020/03/31/Tues-Anxiety.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anxiety" /><published>2020-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/03/31/Tues-Anxiety</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/03/31/Tues-Anxiety.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, my anxiety felt more crippling. I struggled with anxiety since high school. Through the years and through many doctors, I learned about “Candida” which is a yeast overgrowth in my gut. Candida is said to cause anxiety and other symptoms. As I started to heal my gut, I found significant relief but there were still times when it would come back.
Although my anxiety subsided, it surged back with the passing of Beau and the uncertain time we are living in. I learned some techniques to combat the anxiety when it starts to take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise- Move my body to elevate my heart rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting outside- Take a hike, walk, run, bike ride, or just sit on the porch. Being in nature helps reground me. Spring is still happening. The trees are still blooming and the birds are still chirping. It provides a sense of peace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aromatherapy - When my anxiety starts to run rapid, it is soothing to roll essential oil on my chest or just breath the smells in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pray/Worship- For me, reminding myself of truth and the God I serve helps to tackle the feeling of “things are out of my control”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breathe Deep- Laying down and focusing solely on my breath allows tension and thoughts to dissipate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know we are all struggling in our own ways but it does not mean we are alone. I know things feel scary, out of control, and uncertain. Although we cannot control what is going on around us, we can control our response and how we are going to use this time. Let us prevent the fear from consuming us and our anxiety from winning.
We have so much to hope in and hope for. There is beauty and joy in this season. Let us shift our perspective and press into the fulfilling things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="anxiety" /><category term="mindfulness" /><summary type="html">Recently, my anxiety felt more crippling. I struggled with anxiety since high school. Through the years and through many doctors, I learned about “Candida” which is a yeast overgrowth in my gut. Candida is said to cause anxiety and other symptoms. As I started to heal my gut, I found significant relief but there were still times when it would come back. Although my anxiety subsided, it surged back with the passing of Beau and the uncertain time we are living in. I learned some techniques to combat the anxiety when it starts to take over.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/hand-flowers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/hand-flowers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No Sugar-Added Granola Bar recipe</title><link href="/2020/03/27/Granola-Bars.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Sugar-Added Granola Bar recipe" /><published>2020-03-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/03/27/Granola-Bars</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/03/27/Granola-Bars.html">&lt;p&gt;This recipe is very easy to do and the best part is you can prep it ahead of time (like nap time). Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 pitted dates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup hazelnuts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup cashews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup pecans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup pumpkin seeds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 scoops Vital Proteins Collagen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ unsweetened coconut flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup melted coconut oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp pure vanilla extract (omit to keep Whole30)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ almond butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup unsweetened dried cherries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add boiling water to dates and let it soak for about 10 minutes or until softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add all nuts, dates and collagen to a food processor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pulse until it reaches a crumbly texture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer the ingredients to a mixing bowl and stir in cinnamon, salt, dried fruit, and coconut flakes until combined&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the melted coconut oil, almond butter, and vanilla extra in a small bowl and stir until combined&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the wet ingredients to the dry and mix together&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line an 8 x 8-inch square pan with parchment paper and add the mixture in. Press down with hands until it is evenly packed in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover with plastic wrap and freeze for 1.5 – 2 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove from freezer and cut into 20 bars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep in fridge or freezer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to share my No Sugar-Added Granola Bar recipe. It is a versatile and flexible recipe meaning you can use any nuts, nut butter, protein powder, or dried fruit in your pantry. As long as the measurements are the same, it will turn out great. I generally make a big batch, freeze half, and store the rest in the fridge. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="favorite-recipes" /><summary type="html">This recipe is very easy to do and the best part is you can prep it ahead of time (like nap time). Enjoy!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/Granola-Bars.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/Granola-Bars.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wash your Fruits and Veggies</title><link href="/2020/03/26/Thurs-Wash-Produce.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wash your Fruits and Veggies" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2020/03/26/Thurs-Wash-Produce</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/03/26/Thurs-Wash-Produce.html">&lt;p&gt;Washing produce is important to prevent foodborne illness and reducing your exposure to pesticides. For good food hygiene, learn how to wash produce, regardless if it is organic or conventional. When washing your fruits and vegetables, making your own baking soda or salt solution may be the best option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-leafy-greens&quot;&gt;For leafy greens&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill a salad spinner with greens, then fill with water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a teaspoon of baking soda and mix well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soak your greens for a minute, swish, dump, then rinse, and spin dry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;If you don’t have a salad spinner, you can add the greens, water, and baking soda to a bowl, let them soak, drain in a strainer, rinse, then pat leaves dry with a clean lint-free kitchen towel or paper towels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-other-veggies&quot;&gt;For other veggies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill a large bowl or sink with water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add a teaspoon of baking soda (If using a sink, increase the amount of baking soda)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the veggies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soak for a minute or two&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrub with a brush&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rise off the veggies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-fruits&quot;&gt;For fruits&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smooth skinned fruits, such as apples, nectarines, and cherries, can be washed in a baking soda bath the same way as veggies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-berries&quot;&gt;For berries&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berries can be rinsed under cold water in a mesh strainer, then gently patted dry with a clean kitchen towel or paper towels just before you intend to eat them. However, avoid washing the berries until just before eating to avoid the increase of microflora, and mold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt; Salt can also be used in lieu of baking soda. If you need an easy premix solution, I have used @branchbasics and it works great!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="cleaning" /><category term="fruits" /><category term="vegetables" /><summary type="html">Washing produce is important to prevent foodborne illness and reducing your exposure to pesticides. For good food hygiene, learn how to wash produce, regardless if it is organic or conventional. When washing your fruits and vegetables, making your own baking soda or salt solution may be the best option.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/Produce-in-Sink.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/Produce-in-Sink.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>