<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-08T19:17:05-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Health, Healing, and Hope (H3)</title><subtitle>Join me as I catalog my journey of the peaks and valleys of health, healing, and hope (H3 with Laura). I want to share some of my favorite paleo, gluten free, and egg free recipes. I hope to share my thoughts on health related topics and provide meaningful tips.</subtitle><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><entry><title type="html">Strawberry Pecan Crisp</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/08/Strawberry-Pecan-Crisp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strawberry Pecan Crisp" /><published>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/08/Strawberry-Pecan-Crisp</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/08/Strawberry-Pecan-Crisp/">&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we went to a farm and picked strawberries so I obviously had to make a strawberry crisp. It turned out so yummy, I could not wait to share it with you! If you do not have strawberries on hand, no worries as any berries will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strawberry Filling
Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 ½ cup chopped strawberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup honey (or maple syrup)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ tablespoons arrowroot powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tablespoons lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topping&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup gluten free oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7 tablespoons softened grass-fed butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup almond flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup chopped pecans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ fine sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350 F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add chopped strawberries, honey, arrowroot, lemon juice and cinnamon to a 9 by 9 square pan and stir until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a medium size bowl stir together the oats, almond flour, pecans, coconut sugar, vanilla extract and salt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in softened butter and stir until combined (can use a hand mixer but I always use my hands).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the topping mixture to the strawberry filling and spread it out evenly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake for 40-45 minutes or until the filling is bubbling around the edges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy with vanilla ice cream!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt; If using frozen strawberries, let them thaw completely.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes," /><category term="desserts," /><category term="gluten-free," /><category term="egg-free," /><category term="nuts" /><summary type="html">Last weekend we went to a farm and picked strawberries so I obviously had to make a strawberry crisp. It turned out so yummy, I could not wait to share it with you! If you do not have strawberries on hand, no worries as any berries will work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/strawberry-pecan-crisp_oq2c77.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/strawberry-pecan-crisp_oq2c77.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (Living Minimally)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/05/Tues-Letting-Go-of-Stuff/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (Living Minimally)" /><published>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/05/Tues-Letting-Go-of-Stuff</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/05/05/Tues-Letting-Go-of-Stuff/">&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the “Letting Go” series, one of the areas I felt I needed to let go of is unused stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared a little about how important keeping a clean house is for me. During our time at home in these unusual times, we decided to go through everything we own. Living minimally has always sparked my interest but not something I fully understood or practiced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We listened to a podcast with a guest named Joshua Becker and he defined minimalism as “The intentional promotion of the things I most value in life by removing anything that distracts me from it”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shared the goal of minimalism is not about owning the fewest stuff but about pursuing our greatest values and desires with more passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed to figure out what we valued most. For us, it is about experience, the time and financial freedom to do so. We realized we were spending time and money taking care of our stuff, when we would rather be experiencing, traveling, hiking, and having friends over. For example, there is stuff we moved from AK to OK to TN where we did not even open the box. We spent time figuring out where to store those boxes in each residence and money moving them across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one ever looks back on their life thankful for their stuff or the things they bought. I want to make sure that I am able to passionately pursue my hobbies and desires to the fullest. For us, it means removing the things we do not use and practice mindfulness when we purchase something. It is about quality not quantity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not mean I only have 10 pieces of clothing or have nothing on the walls. I am choosing to be intentional about what we keep in our house and what we purchase. I free up mental space if I can walk into my closet and know all the items fit and I will wear them. Ultimately, I want to spend my free time exploring and experiencing. It is mentally and physically taxing to clean, organize, maintain, and tend to things which do not advance my goal of an experience driven lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #tipthursday, I am going to share how we practically are doing this. It is not something done in a week. It can take months. It is also not a one and done but a lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there anything you can let go of? Are there clothes, decorations, or kitchen items taking up space physically but also emotionally and mentally? What are your greatest values and desires? Are you setting yourself up for success by creating time, space and energy in order to pursue them?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="letting-go" /><category term="cleaning" /><category term="mindfulness" /><summary type="html">Continuing with the “Letting Go” series, one of the areas I felt I needed to let go of is unused stuff.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/living-minimally_c2avap.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/living-minimally_c2avap.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (I Am Enough - Part 2)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/30/Thurs-I-Am-Enough-Cont/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (I Am Enough - Part 2)" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/30/Thurs-I-Am-Enough-Cont</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/30/Thurs-I-Am-Enough-Cont/">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I shared about speaking truth into my life and letting go of the lies. One of the biggest lies I allowed in is that I am not enough. If you want to read more about how and why head to my &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough&quot;&gt;#topictuesday post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in letting go of anything is acknowledgment. What is the next step? How do I practically let go of that lie and live in the truth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, it is making sure I am feeding my body, soul and spirit with truth and love. Personally, I wake up and spend time in God’s Word. It grounds me in truth and allows time for reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest in the truth and free the lies. It is a simple concept but requires an arduous effort to master. Do you recognize when shame starts to creep in? It is help to analyze what you are listening to and where your thoughts are taking you. Evaluate your actions and then act. Do not rest in shame, or lies. Shift your mindset and perspective into truth. It may mean taking a minute to breath or verbalize aloud positive self-talk. It may mean reaching out to your spouse or loved one and asking them to pray for you or speak into the lie or situation. It may also mean taking time and reflecting. Anchoring your identity, purpose, and relationships in the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talk a lot about understanding our why. Why do I feel like I am not enough? Why have I allowed shame to shape so much of my life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be vulnerable. Open up those closets you keep shut. Open up to yourself, to a friend, or your partner. Vulnerability creates vulnerability. It brings light and truth into the darkness and lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge to you is rest in the truth and free the lies. How we do that may look different for all of us. What are some of the ways you can live in the truth and free the lies?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">On Tuesday, I shared about speaking truth into my life and letting go of the lies. One of the biggest lies I allowed in is that I am not enough. If you want to read more about how and why head to my #topictuesday post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go Series (I Am Enough)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go Series (I Am Enough)" /><published>2020-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/28/Tues-I-Am-Enough/">&lt;p&gt;As I spent time these last few weeks asking myself what I need to let go of, the notion of “Not feeling like I am enough” seems to be at forefront of my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, I have been a number of sizes in my life. For so long, I believed when I lost the weight I would feel like I was enough. However, as I lost the weight, I began to realize the lie went much deeper than what showed on the outside. When I took my season of rest, it happened right after our wedding and moved away from all my family and friends. I went from loved ones around me, a full-time job, actively involved in a church, and going to school to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was heavier, I overcompensated by doing more and trying to being more. I busied myself by finding my worth in what I did. Fast forward to my season of rest where I started losing weight without trying but I had no one. No friends, no schedule, and no activities. As I felt like I was not enough in one area, I tried extra hard in the another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now looking back on both seasons and living my current one, where I am healthy, I still struggle with not being enough. Here I am healthy but I am not working. I have been married for four years but do not have children. How do I answer when someone asks what I do? I feel guilty because I know it is a privilege to not work and focus on my health but it can also be extremely lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circumstances change. They always will. Do I put my worth in my circumstances? In what I am doing today? In what I look like today? If I did, it would be fleeting. I would not be setting myself up for success but rather disappoint and failure because life is ever changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still learning, growing, processing and practicing how to control my thoughts around this by actively pushing out the lie and speaking truth. I am enough, not because of what I do or what I look like. I am enough because I believe I am enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple weeks, I am going to list more specific ways of letting go. I have to continue to rid my life of this lie and rest in the truth. For #tipthursday, I am going to share how I am practically doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What thought(s) or lie(s) do you need to be free of?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">As I spent time these last few weeks asking myself what I need to let go of, the notion of “Not feeling like I am enough” seems to be at forefront of my mind.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Roasted Butternut Squash</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/24/Roasted-Butternut-Squash/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Roasted Butternut Squash" /><published>2020-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/24/Roasted-Butternut-Squash</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/24/Roasted-Butternut-Squash/">&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday! One of my all-time favorite side dishes is roasted butternut squash. Although, I sometimes opt for the already cubed butternut squash it is noticeably better if you buy it and chop it yourself. It is worth the effort, trust me. I love to use any leftovers we have on salad, my favorite being my &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/03/06/Burger-Up-Salad/&quot;&gt;“Burger Up House Salad”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roasted Butternut Squash
Servings: 4
Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large butternut squash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-4 Tablespoons avocado oil (depending on the size of squash)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 ½ teaspoons Primal Palate BBQ seasoning (or any BBQ seasoning)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon Italian Seasoning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea Salt &amp;amp; Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400F.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut butternut squash into cubes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toss the everything in a bowl until butternut squash is fully coated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put butternut squash in a casserole dish (or cookie sheet with parchment paper)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bake for 50 mins - 1 hour or until the squash is golden and crispy on the edges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="favorite-recipes" /><category term="easy" /><summary type="html">Happy Friday! One of my all-time favorite side dishes is roasted butternut squash. Although, I sometimes opt for the already cubed butternut squash it is noticeably better if you buy it and chop it yourself. It is worth the effort, trust me. I love to use any leftovers we have on salad, my favorite being my “Burger Up House Salad”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/roasted-butternut-squash_iz8eds.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/roasted-butternut-squash_iz8eds.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go (Series - Part 1)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/23/Thurs-Letting-Go-Part-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go (Series - Part 1)" /><published>2020-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/23/Thurs-Letting-Go-Part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/23/Thurs-Letting-Go-Part-1/">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I shared about starting a series related to letting go. Before we start, I think it is important to ponder what we need to let go of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take some time today or this weekend to reflect and journal some of the things/areas you want to let go of. As I started to list out mine, I was shocked with what I am still holding onto. After the first one, the ideas and thoughts kept on flowing. It was clear I needed to write it down. There is something healing about committing it to paper. It is a small step but a first step in letting go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TipThursdays are about small changes leading to big impacts down the road. I believe taking time to journal and actually write down things we need to let go of is an important step in taking back control of our thoughts. I talked about controlling what we can and releasing what we cannot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I will share an area I am letting go of and why. I hope you join me on this journey. Let us take back control over ourselves and let go of the areas keeping us captive and no longer serving us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">On Tuesday, I shared about starting a series related to letting go. Before we start, I think it is important to ponder what we need to let go of.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/letting-go-journal_b2bdcj.jpgs" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/letting-go-journal_b2bdcj.jpgs" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Letting Go (Series)</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/21/Tues-Letting-Go/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Letting Go (Series)" /><published>2020-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/21/Tues-Letting-Go</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/21/Tues-Letting-Go/">&lt;p&gt;If I narrowed down what I learned these past few weeks to one thing, it would be my need to let go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting go of control. Letting go of lies I believed. Letting go of things holding me captive. Letting go of clutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now until May, I am going to focus my #topictuesday and #tipthursdays on things I am practicing letting go. Every Tuesday (for this series) I will share my why and on Thursday I will outline practical ways of letting go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is beauty even in this season. Part of the beauty is the gift of time. I want to use this time to look deeper into my soul, spirit and heart. I want to actively be working towards the best version of myself. I desire to put habits into practice to carry over into all seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us practice letting go. There is freedom in removing the burdens shackling us down. Let us let go so we can fully walk in truth, lightness, and joy and run with endurance the path marked out for us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><category term="mindfulness" /><category term="letting-go" /><summary type="html">If I narrowed down what I learned these past few weeks to one thing, it would be my need to let go.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/bridge-in-woods_wphgny.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/bridge-in-woods_wphgny.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mindful Snacking</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/17/Thurs-Mindful-Snacking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mindful Snacking" /><published>2020-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/17/Thurs-Mindful-Snacking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/17/Thurs-Mindful-Snacking/">&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, I talked about eating how I want to feel. It can be easy to say it aloud but how do we practically live it out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, start with asking yourself why. Why am I reaching for a snack? Next, examine the answer. Is it I am I hungry? I am bored? I am upset and finding myself turning to food for comfort? Only you know the answers and what your body needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you understand your why, there are a few things to ensure mindful snacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way I mindfully snack is by cutting and preparing my vegetables and fruit. After, I put it at eye level in the fridge. Anytime I open the refrigerator, the first thing I see is easily accessible prepared veggies and fruit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Snacker” is in my DNA and honestly always will be. However, I need to moderate the amount I eat so I am not mindlessly consuming. I practice plating my snacks. Taking a whole bag of crackers to the couch to work on something or to watch TV never ends well. Plating my snacks sets me up to avoid overconsumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both tips are indeed simple. Tip Thursdays are all about small changes leading to big impacts down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are some of the ways you are going to practice mindful snacking this week/weekend?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="tip-thursday" /><category term="mindfulness" /><category term="snacks" /><summary type="html">On Tuesday, I talked about eating how I want to feel. It can be easy to say it aloud but how do we practically live it out?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/fridge-snacks_fxsi0y.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/fridge-snacks_fxsi0y.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Greek Salad</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/17/Greek-Salad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greek Salad" /><published>2020-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/17/Greek-Salad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/17/Greek-Salad/">&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday! It is beautiful in Nashville today which means it is the perfect time to grill out and make this easy salad. I generally make this with my &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/04/03/Greek-Tzatziki&quot;&gt;Greek Chicken and Taztziki Sauce&lt;/a&gt;. You can also serve it with crackers or on top of bread for an appetizer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greek Cucumber Salad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servings: 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cucumber diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ - ¾ cup diced tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup crumbled feta (omit for paleo)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons red wine vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon Italian seasoning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;salt &amp;amp; pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop cucumber and tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add to a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix in the rest of the ingredients&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;I generally make it 2-4 hours before serving. It is best to allow the flavors to marinate if time allows&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="recipes" /><category term="paleo" /><category term="gluten-free" /><category term="egg-free" /><category term="salad" /><category term="easy" /><summary type="html">Happy Friday! It is beautiful in Nashville today which means it is the perfect time to grill out and make this easy salad. I generally make this with my Greek Chicken and Taztziki Sauce. You can also serve it with crackers or on top of bread for an appetizer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/Greek-Salad_qr5fmg.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/Greek-Salad_qr5fmg.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Eat How You Want to Feel</title><link href="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/14/Eating-How-You-Want-To-Feel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eat How You Want to Feel" /><published>2020-04-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/14/Eating-How-You-Want-To-Feel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://h3withlaura.com/2020/04/14/Eating-How-You-Want-To-Feel/">&lt;p&gt;Do you eat how you want to feel? Have you ever stopped to think about food in the context of feeling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you want to feel right now? Yes, we are at home more than usual. Yes, we are likely more scared, on edge, and trying to keep anxiety in check but how do you want to feel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would be remiss to put water and gasoline into your car and expect it to run smoothly at peak performance without issue. Garbage in. Garbage out. Why do I find myself always grabbing a bag of chips or ice cream and eating until it is gone? Eating a tub of ice cream may provide instant gratification but leaves an unpaid bill for later. Everything consumed affects mood, health, and relationships. If I want to feel energetic, clear minded, healthy, and active, I fuel my body with nutrient rich foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding our “why” is of the utmost important. Why do I want to eat healthy? Identify first how you want to feel (I assume we all want to feel exceptional) as it helps us understand our purpose and motivation moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am by no means saying I do not consume treats. Eat in moderation and accordance with how I want to feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, I am going to discussing snacking with mindfulness with the uptick in working from home. I will outline practical tips to put mindful snacking into motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you want to feel? Why do you want to feel that way? Are you eating how you want to feel? As you start to ask these questions, exercise grace with yourself (especially in the current circumstances).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Laura Sanders</name></author><category term="topic-tuesday" /><summary type="html">Do you eat how you want to feel? Have you ever stopped to think about food in the context of feeling?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/bowl-of-fruit_ovn5li.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://h3withlaura.com/Blog/bowl-of-fruit_ovn5li.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>